(The tassel crowns the knight.
The sword is snow white.)
(In the silver saddle,
he rides like a shooting star.)
(He kills a man within ten steps.
Invincible he is all the way ahead.)
(He would leave once it's done.
No trace of him is to be found.)
=Sword Snow Stride= (Season 1)
=Episode 3=
Your Highness.
Where are your people?
They are of no help
in the brothel.
I asked them to leave.
Your Highness,
is this the divine horse you just got?
No.
Just an aged horse.
We have plenty of
good horses at the mansion.
Do you want to change one?
I'm used to it.
Alright.
Then I won't talk nonsense.
Let's go now.
Your Highness,
why not get on the horse?
It doesn't allow me to ride.
Are you in a rush?
No.
Alright,
I haven't been back for three years.
Let's take our time
and walk around.
Come on.
Jiang Ni, keep up.
(Tingchao Pavilion)
Did you catch any fish?
I've caught several.
That's enough.
Go back to your room.
No, I can't.
We're eating grilled fish tonight.
You guys
may leave now.
Not you.
Stay here.
Son, look.
There are abundant water plants
over there.
There must be a lot of fish.
Go fishing over there.
Really?
I never lied to you.
Alright.
Sit down.
Thank you
for these three years.
My Lord, you have already
said thank you.
That's not enough.
I've been thinking that
I should give you something.
Meat is fine.
Streaky pork will be the best.
Do you really want to
be a horseman for the rest of your life?
As long as you want,
North Liang can help you
to get back to your business
and reproduce the mien
of Jian Jiuhuang.
My Lord, to be honest,
I've thought about it.
I've had this
with me during these years.
I always felt like I couldn't
let go of my old self.
I've messed with myself for years
without much peace.
Then, let your sword
come out of the box.
After the three-year travel
with Young Master,
I've got
my inner peace.
My Lord, you happen to be here,
please
bear witness for me.
Jian Jiuhuang
was already dead
on the city wall.
From now on,
I'm just Old Huang
by Young Master's side.
Tell me when the fish are grilled.
His Highness is back!
Don't let him see you.
He is lustful.
I heard that he has taken
a lot of girls back to his mansion.
He looks handsome.
It's not a bad choice.
This servant also looks cute.
So pretty.
Where does this cute boy come from?
You don't understand.
But he doesn't look manly.
What's wrong with your eyes?
How can a man be so pretty like me?
We're going to a brothel.
It's not appropriate
to say you're a girl.
Your Highness, you're back!
It's been years.
All the girls are missing you
all the time.
Don't talk too much.
Lead the horse to the backyard.
Go.
I finished it.
That's fast.
You're pretty like Old Huang.
We have no fruit now.
I don't need to go in.
Then you're
the fruit.
Come on.
What?
What do you mean?
I'll pay you, OK?
(Lingzhou Zijin Brothel)
(Zijin Brothel)
What game is His Highness playing?
He even brings two girls here.
How dare you
gossip about His Highness?
I'm sorry.
How much do these cost?
A dozen taels, I guess.
A dozen?
These are cheap ones.
Your Highness,
the new belle is here.
What's your name?
(Belle of Zijin Brothel Yu Youwei)
Yu Youwei.
Nice name.
How honored I am
to meet
Your Highness here today.
You know who I am?
General Chu told me.
Your Highness,
her sword dance is famous.
You can't see her waist
if not the dance.
Then,
Miss Yu, please.
I can dance
two kinds of sword dance.
One is
for the
common people.
What about the other one?
The other
is only
for my lover.
Why?
Because the latter one
is pretty flirtatious.
That's great.
If Your Highness can come
with me to the backyard,
then I can dance
to Your Highness alone.
Let's go
and see how flirtatious it is.
Double blades?
It's not common.
The tea is freshly brewed.
Your Highness, do you wanna try it?
No.
I just want to see your dance.
The flirtatious one.
West Chu's Sword Dance?
It's sharpened?
(Chu)
You shouldn't have made use
of the dance.
The Halberd Troops of West Chu
outside Lingzhou City tried to kill me.
What you did would only
remind me of West Chu's Sword Dance.
Assassination doesn't need
to be so complicated.
Are you from the Chu?
Why do you want to kill me?
Xu Xiao wiped out the Chu.
Who else should I kill?
That's not a right way to talk about it.
That was a national war between
Liyang and West Chu,
not a private feud.
Even if Xu Xiao had not led the troops,
someone else would have
wiped out West Chu as well.
If you want to take revenge,
you should go to Liyang's royal family.
There is no reason for you
to keep targeting my family.
That's not only a national war.
Then what else do you think it is?
If the Great Chu was defeated,
we could surrender.
But what did Xu Xiao do?
He led his troops into the palace
and killed His Majesty and the Empress!
Not only that,
hundreds of people in the palace
all didn't survive,
even the young princess was beheaded!
Is she highly skilled in martial arts?
She can't do martial arts.
Just sword dance.
That's good.
Please take Jiang Ni here.
Wait!
Even if I can't kill you,
I will never let myself be humiliated!
Can you wait for a moment?
Until that person comes.
Why should I go?
You can ask him yourself.
Did he get horny?
It's really an assassination!
Look!
Even the girl in the brothel
can't stand such a rascal like you.
That's the common wish!
She danced West Chu's Sword Dance.
You're from the Chu?
Show her
your dagger.
She is about to kill herself.
Don't bother.
I can do it myself.
Wait a second!
Since you know West Chu's Sword Dance,
you must not be a civilian, are you?
My father was an official.
My mother was the sword servant.
Then you must know this dagger.
Divine Token?
You said
the young princess was beheaded.
Have you ever seen her head?
What do you mean?
Xu Xiao spread the rumor
of the beheading.
The Princess is not dead.
She's standing right here.
Have you ever seen the Empress
of West Chu?
You're really…?
They say I look like my mother.
It seems to be true now.
I'm Jiang Ni,
princess of the conquered nation.
Your Highness!
(Mansion of Lord of North Liang)
Your Highness.
You're back.
I'll go make the tea now.
No hurry.
Find her a room.
Your Highness, where did you
get this confidante from?
Yu Youwei,
the belle of Zijin Brothel.
Settle her down first.
Yes.
(Wutong House)
Where is my python whip?
Is it this one?
Yes.
How is this room?
Not bad.
What do you think?
It's good as long as you like it.
Bedding should be replaced
with new ones.
OK.
I'll ask them to prepare it.
She looks to be smiling all day.
She is the one
with the deepest thoughts.
Let's get in.
Your Highness, please.
Don't call me that.
I'm Jiang Ni.
There is no princess
after our nation fell.
I know you have something to ask.
Let's talk inside.
General Chu, why are you still
kneeling in my courtyard?
You're not going back to your battalion?
Your Highness, please just call me
Fatty Lushan.
I don't dare to.
If I call you that again,
I won't know
which assassin you'll take me to again.
Your Highness,
I really didn't know that Yu Youwei
was an assassin!
General Chu, you should go back.
I have no official rank
nor military position.
I feel embarrassed
to have a third-ranking officer
kneel in my courtyard.
I'm willing to be punished.
(Ruide Hall)
You'd better think twice.
It's not late to leave now.
I put Your Highness in danger.
I should take punishment.
But it was never planned by me.
I can tell nothing else
even if Your Highness kills me.
Really?
Let me kill you then.
Just ask whatever you want to know.
They all said
Xu Xiao had killed everyone
in the palace.
And…
And beheaded me?
Was it not Xu Xiao?
Back then,
the capital city of Chu was captured
by Xu Xiao,
but his men
never killed prisoners
or hurt civilians.
However, it was not only the
North Liang army that entered the city.
Some of the bigwigs of Liyang
were also waiting
to rush into the palace.
What did they want to do?
The royal concubines of Chu.
The noble status
made them more excited.
What a batch of rascals!
It was Xu Xiao
who closed the palace gate
before anyone else
to prevent others from entering.
But he was not the Emperor of Liyang,
so he couldn't hold back for long.
Then my father
begged to die,
and everyone in the palace
was willing to die with him.
(Palace of West Chu)
(Xuanzheng Hall)
Xu Xiao promised to keep me alive.
(Juvenile Jiang Ni)
Don't look back.
Look forward.
After that day,
the Princess of West Chu died.
Only Jiang Ni is left.
You have been here
among all these years?
Where else can I go?
Have you
never thought of revenge?
I was little back then
and couldn't remember everything.
I just remember
my father stroked my head
and told me to live well.
I see.
What else do you want to ask?
Are you…?
What's that mincement about?
Go ahead.
Are you like the two girls just now?
Like what?
You are all Xu Fengnian's…?
I'm not that kind of maid!
Xu Fengnian didn't…?
He has more than 20 maids
and never touched any of us.
But the rumors said…
The rumors said
Xu Fengnian is a womanizer.
The rumors also said that I was dead.
Alright.
(Ruide Hall)
Dead?
I…
I am still breathing.
My Lord,
the news that
His Highness is whipping General Chu
has been spread.
At the door came many generals
to ask for a meeting.
I won't meet them.
Then…
Then
what about His Highness?
Let him do it.
But
I'm afraid General Chu
Let's talk about you.
Are you still killing Xu Fengnian?
Your accomplices
are also in Lingzhou.
For the sake of Chu,
I'll find a chance for you
to escape and join them.
I don't have accomplices.
Then how did you enter Zijin Brothel
and how did you become the new belle?
I don't know.
Never mind.
I really don't know.
I have been watched among the years
and only dancing.
They told me to prepare for
assassinating Xu Fengnian
and avenging Chu.
Who are they?
I asked before.
They never answered me.
Where were you locked?
It was a big yard
with heavy guard.
I've never left there
so I don't know where it is.
But I could hear chanting sometimes.
What about the people
who took you there?
They left.
They just told me
to wait for Xu Fengnian.
Sounds like
you're just a puppet.
Do you know Chu Lushan?
Never heard of him.
Then why did he
take Xu Fengnian to you?
(Ruide Hall)
Your Highness.
General Ning Emei
from Fengzi Battalion
shows greetings to Your Highness.
I know you.
You led the troops to pick me up.
Your Highness,
why are you whipping General Chu?
Are you greeting me
or questioning me?
I don't dare to.
I just wonder why.
He took me to the brothel
and I met an assassination.
Can that be a reason?
Has General Chu admitted
that he planned it?
Would you admit it if it were you?
Then, is there any evidence?
No, so what?
It's unreasonable to impose lynching
without evidence.
I remember you were with
your halberd last time.
You don't bring it with you?
I don't dare to meet Your Highness
with that.
It's better to take it with you
when negotiating.
North Liang has its own laws
which don't depend on the weapon
nor superiority and inferiority.
There are laws
and there is no superiority.
Nice speaking.
Your Highness flattered me.
I'm speaking bluntly.
Do you know that even Xu Xiao
doesn't dare to speak to me like that?
Who do you think you are?
I'm Ning Emei, Military General
from Fengzi Battalion.
Alright,
I bear you in mind.
The laws won't work. What to do?
Your Highness, please think twice.
Think about what?
If you let the army down,
no rule will work in the three states.
When the time comes,
can Your Highness still be able to
be in charge of Xu's army?
Guard!
Take this rebel to prison!
Whether it's planned by Chu Lushan
or not,
your assassination
is not that easy.
You were only taught with sword dance
but no fighting skills.
If they really wanted you
to kill Xu Fengnian,
that's
unreasonable.
What do they want then?
Xu Fengnian was also assassinated
by Chu people on his way back.
Was it related to my assassination?
I don't know.
But I feel that this is not done yet.
It's fine as long as Your Highness
is not involved.
I told you not to call me that again.
I'm leaving.
Please don't get angry.
I'm not angry.
I need to work.
The books in his room
need to be dried every month.
So annoying.
My Lord,
His Highness is sending Ning Emei
to the prison.
Alright.
His Highness
told the maid to send a message
to the gate.
What is it?
His Highness said
Ning Emei came to negotiate
and is in prison now.
If anyone of you still wants
to help Chu Lushan,
don't kneel here
and come directly in.
My Lord,
Chen Zhibao is here.
Now
he is heading to His Highness.
I got it.
It's cold.
Alright,
I'll change it right now.
His Highness,
Chen Zhibao is coming.
White Chen?
You know him?
Chen Zhibao, War Immortal in White.
Xu Xiao's henchman.
The top general in North Liang
and the top one of the Adopted Six.
The backbone of North Liang.
It's said that
he is the only one capable to take over
North Liang after Xu Xiao.
Sounds like there is nothing
to do with me.
You're also well-known.
Chen Zhibao is the hope of North Liang
and you are the shame of North Liang.
You're both famous.
Have some tea
and wait for White Chen.
(Ruide Hall)
Don't stand in the way.
I can't even see him.
You're also here to persuade me?
Chu Lushan is
the general I look down upon the most.
I have told them
that one day
I will send him to hell.
If you really want to kill him,
I can do it for you.
The problem is,
do you really want to kill him?
What is it?
Head.
The person who gave your portrait out
and sent the belle
to the brothel.
Who is it?
A military officer.
You don't know him.
Only an officer
can make such big trouble?
That's interesting.
He is the most brutal
and ridiculous one among the generals.
But this devil happens to be
most loyal to you.
I guess you whipped him
just to show the North Liang army.
In that way,
if someone wants to harm you,
the first choice to draw over
is the resentful Chu Lushan.
And you're also waiting.
The one who comes to save him
may be the murderer
who planned to kill you.
What a coincidence.
You're here now.
That's a harsh whip.
It's hard for him
to suffer for you.
Your Highness, please whip hard
later when you punish me.
It has to be hard enough
to be believed by others.
If you want to fish,
the bait must be put enough.
Your Highness.
Let's have a word alone.
They all say
you should be the one
to take over North Liang.
In contrast,
I, the son of Lord of North Liang,
am treated as a joke by others.
What do you think?
Didn't you ask for a talk?
Why don't you speak?
Did you question the belle?
She grew up being raised in a mansion,
practicing sword dance every day
just to stab me with that sword.
She doesn't know
who raised her.
She was just sent there.
Kill her.
No way.
She is pretty.
You can go meet her.
Maybe you will like her.
The assassination outside the city
and the sword dance
were just to make you suspect that
a rebel is hiding in the army.
You already fell into the trap
when you used Chu Lushan
to find him out.
Once you feel suspicious,
the army will be in a mess.
Kill that belle,
together with the officer's head,
so that the whole matter can be over.
Over?
That means no more investigation?
We should keep on investigating,
but on the surface,
this is over.
So, that officer
was not the murderer.
Just to end it on the surface,
he was beheaded.
He broke the military law
and had long been sentenced to death.
He had been sentenced to death
but he died now
just to end this up?
How many endings like this
are you hiding?
There are internal
and external problems.
The three states of North Liang
can't be in a mess.
That's why you, Chen Zhibao,
are the backbone of North Liang.
Yes,
I am.
I just told you
that the belle is pretty.
I'm reluctant to kill her.
What to do now?
♪ The flower of pain ♪